Reedham Patel

reedham.plutonium@gmail.com

(438) 389-8335

GitHub | Portfolio | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

As a highly skilled video game developer with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and a diploma's degree in Video Game Programming, I bring over 4 years of experience in the video game industry. With my in-depth knowledge of both the Unreal and Unity game engines, I have honed my skills in creating immersive gaming experiences. I am passionate about crafting engaging and captivating games that transport players to new worlds. Let's work together to create the next great video game!

EXPERIENCE

Game Developer (Unreal/C++)

Dynasty Loop, Montreal, Canada / May 2022 - Present

Working on an unannounced Game project.

- Designed and developed code architecture and AI system from scratch.
- Developing the gameplay and mechanics for the game project with a team of 10+ personnel.
- Creating a procedural animation tool that allows to animate 50 different characters.
- Integrated 3D pathfinding in game.

Environment:C++, C#, Unreal, Unity, Jira, Perforce, Unreal Shader, Miro.

Unity Developer (VR Application)

Hausvalet, Montreal, Canada / Oct 2021 -May 2022

Created a VR application that allows users to browse rental properties in the VR environment.

- Redesign and develop the software architecture for existing applications.
- Modify code structure and make applications more optimized for low-end devices.
- Add In-Application voice and video communication system with AGORA.
- Making API Calls more secure and more efficient.
- Crafted JSON based localization.
- Developed Top-Down Singleton Factory pattern based architecture.

APP Store Link :- https://apps.apple.com/ca/app/hausvalet-vr/id1596353498

Environment: Unity, C#, Agora, ReactJS, NodeJS, Unity VR, C++.

Game Developer

Maruti Games, Ahmedabad / April 2018 – November 2019

- Designed and developed an endless runner game or turn- based strategy game in unity/Unreal.
- Integrated monetization tools in the game.
- Developed Level progression system.
- Implemented AI Framework for basic behavior(FSM).

Environment:C++,C#, Unity,Unreal.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Click the link below to see video game projects that I created using the powerful game engines of Unreal and Unity. These projects have been a labor of love, with countless hours spent crafting every detail to create an immersive gaming experience. From the stunning graphics to the engaging gameplay, these projects are a testament to the potential of modern game development.

Link:- My Personal Projects

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming languages
C#, C++, JAVA, Python.
External Libs/Langs/Software
OpenGL, Git, GitHub, Perforce.
Game Engines
Unity, Unreal.
IDE and Other tools
Visual Studio, Rider, Miro.

EDUCATION

Institute supérieur d'informatique ISI, Montréal (2020 - 2022) Video Game Programming (A.C.S)

Gujarat Technological University, India (2014 - 2018) Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science